Silvia Taliana

Adelaide | South Australia Phone | 0405 794 960 Email | silviataliana2@gmail.com

Linkedin | https://www.linkedin.com/in/silvia-taliana-web-developer/
Github | https://github.com/silvia-taliana
Portfolio | https://silvia-taliana.github.io/my-biography/

A passionate and highly motivated full stack web developer with a keen eye for detail, excellent critical thinking and problem solving skills and a strong interest in design. Ability to work under pressure, excellence in training less experienced staff and providing a high level of customer service.

Technical Skills

Front end JavaScript | JQuery | React | AJAX | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap **Back end** Node.js | MySQL | MongoDB | Express | JSON | Handlebars

Projects

My Budget Pal

A MERN stack application that provides users the tools they require to easily see where and how they spend their money, create achievable saving goals and help users spend their money wisely. My Budget Pal also utilises Auth0 and has a mobile first responsive design.

Technologies used: MongoDB | Express | React | Node | Auth0 | Recharts npm | React-Bootstrap Deployed | https://blooming-island-79334.herokuapp.com/ Github | https://github.com/silvia-taliana/my-budget-pal

Hendrix

A review website where users are able to review businesses they have visited, create their own business pages to be reviewed by others and also chat live to business owners if they would like to.

 $Tools\ and\ Technologies:\ HTML\ |\ CSS\ |\ JavaScript\ |\ Node.js\ |\ Handlebars\ |\ MySQL\ |\ Sequelize\ |\ Socket.io\ Deployed\ |\ \underline{https://powerful-cliffs-81150.herokuapp.com/}$

Github | https://github.com/silvia-taliana/hendrix

Tech Blog

A blog site that allows users to create accounts, read and create blogs, and comment on other user's blogs. Additionally, user's passwords are protected by encryption when creating an account.

Tools and Technologies: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Node.js | Handlebars | MySQL | Sequelize

 $Deployed \mid \underline{https://damp\text{-}chamber\text{-}65697.herokuapp.com/}$

Github | https://github.com/silvia-taliana/mvc-tech-blog

Nursing Employment History

SA Pathology | Adelaide SA | Aug 2018 to current Registered Nurse

Gained management experience of the company in charge of last minute roster changes,

complaints management and handling staff questions and concerns

- Training and leadership skills for teams of phlebotomists
- Experience working with people from different backgrounds and all ages

Corporate Health Group | Adelaide SA | Aug 2017 to Aug 2018 Registered Nurse

- Management of workplace injuries and minor emergencies
- Conducted general health screens including drug and alcohol testing
- Exceptional skills in de-escalation of aggressive clients

Ridleyton Greek Home for the Aged | Adelaide SA | Dec 2015 to Oct 2017 Registered Nurse

- In charge of looking after between 30 to 120 residents at a time, writing care plans and continuously monitoring and assessing health care requirements
- Managing teams of Enrolled Nurses and Carers, providing training and direction especially during emergencies
- Collaborating with Doctors and allied health professionals to ensure the best possible care is received for the residents

Other Employment History

Skycity Adelaide Casino | Adelaide SA | March 2012 to July 2016 Bar Attendant / Cocktail Waitress

• Providing a high level of customer service to customers

Buckingham Arms Hotel | Adelaide SA | June 2009 to April 2012 Waitress

Courses and Certificates

Basic Life Support | Achieved June 2020

Basic Life Support Trainer Course | Achieved Jan 2021

Advanced Life Support | Achieved July 2018

DCSI Vulnerable Person Related Police Clearance | Obtained Jul 2018

DCSI Working With Children Police Clearance | Obtained May 2021

National Police Clearance | Obtained 18 June 2018

Senior First Aid (including CPR) | Achieved Mar 2018

Understanding Vaccines and the National Immunisation Program | Achieved Feb 2018

Collecting Specimens for Drugs of Abuse Testing Course | Achieved Aug 2017

ANMF Venepuncture Course | Achieved Sep 2017

ANMF Wound Management Course | Achieved Sep 2016

Education

UX/UI Coding Boot Camp | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development Adelaide University | Completed June 2021

Bachelor of Nursing

University of South Australia | Graduated 2015